

dakotadorn12@gmail.com | | C: 507-251-8048 | Mount Horeb, WI 53572

## **Summary**

Motivated and proficient GIS Specialist with nearly five years of professional data management experience, and eight years of working with related data software. Demonstrated skill in database management, as well as data visualization. Continuously looking for ways to add value and efficiency to workflows and products. Takes pride in working for a public entity, knowing that my work directly benefits numerous stakeholders and individuals in society.

## **Skills Highlights**

- ArcMap 10.7/ArcGIS Pro 2.5 and extensions
- ArcGIS Online
- Proficient in Python and SQL
- Experience using Tableau
- Experienced in scientific writing and field reports
- Exposure to HTML5, Javascript, C, and CSS
- Microsoft Office Suite
- Website design and updating
- AutoCAD/Civil 3D
- Data management

## Experience

City Of Fitchburg | Fitchburg, WI GIS Specialist/Engineering Technician 05/2017 - Current

- Administered all aspects of the GIS data program at the City
- Created and managed Both internal and public facing applications
- Created and managed both the Open Data Policy and Open Data Portal
- Mapped critical City infrastructure both in the field and from provided engineered record drawings
- Prepared plan sets in AutoCAD for City projects
- Maximized productivity and reduced delays by increasing efficiency and accuracy of data uploads.
- Provided visualizations and data driven analytics to numerous departments for use in public meetings, as well as project planning.
- Responded to all internal and external records requests.

Wisconsin Army National Guard | River Falls, WI

Infantryman

11/2011 - 11/2017

- Completed fifteen weeks of basic combat training and advanced individual training at Fort Benning, GA
- Use geospatial tools and technologies in the field to aid my unit in missions
- Led diverse training simulations to prepare teams for combat and emergency situations
- Achieved high marks on evaluations consistently over my 6-year enlistment through outstanding job duty performance, volunteerism and attention to detail in leadership and weapons proficiency
- Was awarded three Army Achievement Medals for leadership and performing duties above my rank

City Of Monona | Monona, WI GIS/Civil Engineering Technician 05/2016 - 05/2017

- Designed an outfall survey and conducted the survey on all of the city's stormwater outfalls
- Provide mapping and cartographic skills for city maps and visualizations
- Conduct utility locates to increase the accuracy of City GIS utility data layers

City of Fitchburg | Fitchburg, WI **Parks and Forestry Assistant** 05/2016 - 05/2017

- Improve and manage the City's expansive tree inventory and datasets
- Manage and update the department's web page
- Engage in community outreach programs and events as a representative from the Forestry Department

University of Wisconsin - Eau Claire | Eau Claire, WI Researcher/Data Analyst 06/2015 - 12/2015

- Conducted admission pattern analysis for the university in partnership with the admissions office
- Used Microsoft Excel to perform data standardization on large statewide data sets
- Utilized the ArcGIS Business Analyst extension to extrapolate data and locate patterns
- Presented my work at a regional conference

## **Education**

University of Wisconsin- Eau Claire | Eau Claire, WI **Bachelor of Science** in Environmental Geography And GIS 12/2015

- 3.28 GPA
- Cum laude graduate